<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to Jet Tech blog.</title>
    <link>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog</link>
    <description>This is the Jet Technology blog</description>
    <item>
      <title>Jet's Tech Talk Weekly Series</title>
      <guid>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog/blog/2015/07-14-tech-talk-weekly</guid>
      <link>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog/blog/2015/07-14-tech-talk-weekly/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 08:55:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One lovely afternoon in mid-March, back in our Montclair, NJ offices, our awesome &lt;a href="http://extroverteddeveloper.com/"&gt;Jim Wallace&lt;/a&gt; took the initiative to start organizing weekly tech talks. Originally, we envisioned gathering to simply watch a conference video that we all wish we'd seen live. Our inaugural video was Bart de Smet's &lt;a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/cloud-rx"&gt;Cloud-scale Event Processing using Rx.&lt;/a&gt;. We threw in some company-sponsored pizza to make sure more of us showed up. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
      <image>ttw/tomas3.JPG</image>
      <author>Rachel Reese</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On how Jet chose F#</title>
      <guid>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog/blog/2015/03-22-on-how-jet-chose</guid>
      <link>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog/blog/2015/03-22-on-how-jet-chose/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 16:38:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;In the beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Jet prototype was written by our CTO, Mike Hanrahan, in his basement, in WCF. After the first developers were brought on, the first proper version of our site was spun up with CoffeeScript. However, Mike knew from the outset that he wanted to use F#, at least for the pricing engine, because of the benefits you often hear about F#: less code leading to fewer bugs, as well as code that is more robust and safer because of the type system, to name a few. As a company, we weren't sure that we should have F# anywhere else, though. After all, we're building an e-commerce web site. Isn't the web fully in the domain of C#? Plus, many of the developers on the team had an object-oriented or imperative background -- what if we wasted too much time figuring out this new language before we could even be productive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we started building two solutions: a C# solution and an F# solution, to see where they would take us. In the end, we chose to stick with the F# path. The main reason: we were able to deliver the same functionality with far less code. This clearly eases maintainability and reduces bugs. If you've been part of the F# community for any length of time, you know that this is a very well known feature of the language and a commonly cited reason to switch to F#. However, we had a few other unique-to-Jet reasons that we wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
      <image></image>
      <author>Rachel Reese</author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jet sponsors the F# Software Foundation!</title>
      <guid>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog/blog/2015/01-12-jet-sponsors-FSSF</guid>
      <link>http://jet.github.io/FsBlog/blog/2015/01-12-jet-sponsors-FSSF/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;What is the F# Software Foundation?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The F# Software Foundation is a community-run non-profit Corporation that aims to promote and benefit the F# Programming Language. It began in 2012, and was organized formally into a non-profit in late 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Foundation, including additional &lt;a href="http://foundation.fsharp.org/history"&gt;history&lt;/a&gt;, or to read the &lt;a href="http://foundation.fsharp.org/"&gt;mission statement&lt;/a&gt; and latest &lt;a href="http://foundation.fsharp.org/board_meeting_minutes"&gt;board meeting minutes&lt;/a&gt; of the F# Software Foundation, see the &lt;a href="http://fsharp.org"&gt;fsharp.org&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
      <image>balloons.jpg</image>
      <author>Rachel Reese</author>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>